insidermonkey.com 2019-07-17

# Privacy Policy - Insider Monkey

Dear Valued Visitor,

We have noticed that you are using **an ad blocker software**. 

Although advertisements on the web pages may degrade your experience, our business certainly depends on them and we can only keep providing you high-quality research based articles as long as we can display ads on our pages.

To view this article, you can disable your ad blocker and refresh this page or simply [**login**](https://www.insidermonkey.com/login).

We only allow registered users to use ad blockers. You can [**sign up for free by clicking here**](https://www.insidermonkey.com/signup) or you can [**login**](https://www.insidermonkey.com/login) if you are already a member.

This is the Privacy Policy for Insider Monkey website owned and operated by Koalaguide, LLC ("we","us" and "our site").

Last update date: 2019-02-08

### Summary

We collect your data directly or via our partners to provide access to the website. We track minimum personal information as possible and only collect additional data (such as your email or account data) for free and paid membership services. We respect your privacy rights and we will comply with your wishes to remove your data according to your wishes if you contact us.

### 1\. The data we collect:

**Traffic Data:** We automatically track and collect the following categories of information when you visit our Site: (1) IP addresses; (2) domain servers; (3) types of computers accessing the Site; and (4) types of web browsers used to access the Site (collectively “Traffic Data”). We store Traffic Data in our server logs when you access the website as part of standard server operation. We keep our server logs encrypted and only use it for technical operations to keep our website running. Additionally, to track possible security breaches we store your IP address in our database when you attempt to login to the website or try to download a paid newsletter.

**Data via Cookies:** A cookie is a small data file containing information, such as a user's login name, that is written to the user's hard drive by a web server and used to track the pages visited. In addition to cookies placed by Insider Monkey or its agents, advertisers and third-party advertising vendors, including Google, that serve ads onto our websites, and other third party partners may use their own cookies or other tracking technologies for advertising or other purposes.

We use encrypted cookies to keep you signed in to our website and store your viewing preferences. Additionally our partners use cookies:

  * To collect and provide us anonymized/aggregated analytics data
  * To improve your advertisement experience by showing you more relevant ads

You can also access our website by disabling cookie functionality from your browser but this would prevent you from being signed in.

You can adjust your personalization settings by **clicking here**. We use an IAB Complaint Consent Management Platform to manage your consent and share with our advertising partners.

**Account Data:** Currently, we do not require users to become members of Insider Monkey in order to have access to the free commentary, analysis and news available on Insider Monkey. However, if you would like to receive one or more of our newsletters and certain services we require you to register to become a member. In order to register, you will have to supply us with your email address and choose a unique User Name and Password and fill out the registration form. Your password is encrypted in our database, preventing us from seeing it.

We request some additional information to enable you to purchase newsletters from our website:

  * Billing Name
  * Billing Address
  * Credit Card Information

We don’t store your billing and credit card information in our database. This information is stored by our PCI compliant payment processor partner, **[Stripe Inc](https://stripe.com/)**.

All of our website functionality is provided via HTTPS, effectively encrypting all the communication between you and our servers.

### 2\. How we use your data

We use the data collected above:

  * To provide core website services
  * To avoid technical failures and prevent security breaches
  * To send you emails for the notifications and alerts that you have explicitly subscribed (If you wish to unsubscribe from those emails you should visit https://www.insidermonkey.com/my-account/notifications/ after logging in.)
  * To send you emails to promote our newsletters or new services. (If you wish to unsubscribe from these emails, you can click on the unsubscribe link on those emails or you can directly contact us.)
  * To provide you personalized advertising and improve onsite experience. (We use Ezoic to provide personalization and analytic services on this website, as such Ezoic's privacy policy is in effect and can be reviewed here.)
  * To collect website analytics to monitor performance and security issues.

Insider Monkey does not sell or disclose personal information about you described above to other people or nonaffiliated companies, except to provide you with products or services, when we have your permission, or under the following circumstances:

  * In response to subpoenas, court orders, or legal process, or otherwise to cooperate with law enforcement agencies or state and federal regulators;
  * We provide the information to our subsidiaries and affiliated companies;
  * We provide the information on a confidential basis to nonaffiliated companies we engage as contractors or agents to perform services for us, such as maintaining software. Information will be shared with such contractors only to the extent reasonably necessary for them to perform services on our behalf, and pursuant to confidentiality obligations;
  * If we sell or otherwise transfer substantially all of our assets related to any website that we own or operate and any product or service that we offer. In that event, we will require such third party to honor our then-current Privacy Policy, until the third party provides you with notice of changes to our Privacy Policy and permits you to exercise any rights you may have under applicable law to limit disclosures of information about you;
  * We may disclose all the information we collect as described above to other companies such as direct marketers to perform marketing services on our behalf, or to third parties with whom we have joint marketing agreements; and
  * We may share with third parties certain pieces of aggregated, non-personal information, such as the number of users who clicked on a particular link or how many users clicked on a particular advertisement. Such information does not identify you individually.

Whenever Insider Monkey changes its privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, and other places we deem appropriate.

### 3\. Users aged under 13

In compliance with Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (“COPPA”), this Site is not directed at children under the age of 13 and we do not intend to collect any personal identifiable information, such as name, home address, e-mail address, telephone number, or social security number, from children under the age of 13. If you are under the age of 13, please do not provide us with your personal identifiable information. If you have any reason to believe that a child under the age of 13 has provided us with his or her personal identifiable information, please contact us immediately for removal of that information from our databases.

### 4\. How to ask us to delete your data

You can send you data removal requests via our **[contact page](https://www.insidermonkey.com/contact-us/)**.

In addition, you can directly contact our Data Protection Officer (DPO) - **[Meena Krishnamsetty](mailto:meena@insidermonkey.com?subject=Contact%20Request).**

Additionally, you can delete your own account by logging in and **[visiting your account page.](https://www.insidermonkey.com/my-account/profile/)**

### Contact Information

If you have any questions or suggestions regarding our privacy policy, please contact the editor of Insider Monkey, or send an email to ** .**
